RAHUL KASHYAP

 $\underline{+91\text{-}8448443891} \cdot \underline{2870.rahul@gmail.com} \cdot \underline{@linkedin.com/in/rahul2870}$ New Delhi, India

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Mastering the art of the **MERN stack with 3 year of experience** like a virtuoso, I bring to the table a delightful blend of MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js expertise. With a dash of internship experience in the realms of Linux, Nginx, and AWS, I've dipped my toes in the DevOps pool. Currently navigating the labyrinthine wonders of Docker and Kubernetes, because why settle for simplicity when you can embrace complexity Forever chasing the elusive thrill of technological mastery, I'm your go-to guy for injecting a dose of innovation into any project.

STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

React.js & Redux MongoDb & Sequelize DB Node.js & Express.js Project Management
Python & Bash scripting
React-Native (Android)

Linux, Nginx & AWS.

* Docker & Kubernetes (L)

* Jenkins & Ansible (L)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

EliteMindz - Janak Puri . New Delhi Full Stack Developer

October 2023 - Present

Played a pivotal role in driving projects forward, taking charge of leadership responsibilities while spearheading the design and implementation of new systems and services. Developed solutions aimed at improving software quality, notably enhancing video and PDF rendering capabilities.

Accomplishments:

- Managed team and created of a CMS with role-based access (admin with super level access, teacher with PDF and video upload capabilities, and student access for ordered material listing).
- Implemented PDF compression and video chunking for optimized quality and size.
- Integrated CCavenue and Jodo payment gateways, along with SMS services, to facilitate payment orders flow.
- Manages calls and project requirements.

<u>Tech Stack</u>: React.js, Node.js (HLS & CMS), Sequelize DB and Linux (Nginx).

<u>Spraxa solutions pvt ltd</u> - Ghaziabad . UP Full Stack Developer

Jan 2022 - Jun 2023 (1yr 6mos)

Contributed to a skilled team, mastering multi-feature and microservices handling, as well as debugging techniques. Managed Steris' in-house asset management software effectively.

Accomplishments:

- Supported hospital products, ensured high quality and reliability.
- Resolved client issues through effective communication and problem-solving.
- Adapted to multiple libraries and frameworks, gained experience with license authorization and MongoDB aggregation.
- Reviewed code for quality, maintainability and continuous learning.

Tech Stack: React.js (MUI,AntD), Node.js (Cron-jobs,Socket.IO), MongoDB (Aggregation)

Softway Solutions

Jun 2020 - Dec 2021 (1yr 6mos)

MERN Stack Developer (Remote)

Developed Node.js APIs for websites and business panels, enhancing performance. Addressed client concerns, collaborated with mentors for resolutions. Adapted to evolving needs, troubleshooted application issues, and pursued continuous learning for skill enhancement.

Accomplishments:

- Developed APIs using Node.js for websites and business panels, improving functionality and performance.
- Resolved client issues by identifying key points, collaborating with mentors for timely resolution and Adapted to changing development needs.
- Pursued continuous learning to enhance development skills and deliver high-quality projects.

Tech Stack: React.js, Next.js, Node.js, MongoDB, React-Native

<u>Platos Foods Private Limited</u> - Chennai . Tamil Nadu React.js Developer (Intern)

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020 (6 mos)

Contributed to React.js components, adding bill export functionality independently, actively engaged in code reviews and agile development, and continuously sought opportunities for learning and application improvement.

Tech Stack: React.js (MUI) & Firebase.

EDUCATION

Coding Ninjas career camp

MERN Stack
2023 - (Jul - Sep)

DU - Keshav Mahavidyalaya - (70%)

BSC (H) - Computer Science 2018 - 2022

Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) - (82%)

PCM - Computer Science

2016 - 2018

PERSONAL PROJECT(S)

Assist Pedia - assistpedia.com

· Categorised content and services deliveries.

Fan Universe - fan-universe.vercel.app

URL: https://fan-universe.vercel.app

Merchant based ecommerce with admin panel and user accounts.

Assist Mate - assistmates.web.app

URL: https://assistmates.web.app

URL: https://assistpedia.com

Blogs and posts content listing and creation with rich dashboard.

Bet App - React Native bet-app

• App with betting Odds on sports and Event, live room games(7) for both Android and IOS.

Lets, connect guys and build something cool.